# Michael D. Harrington

## Designer / Developer

me@michaeldharrington.com (908) 334-0291

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Design-driven web developer with strengths in user interface design, Javascript, and React development. Strong command of design software for prototyping and development hand-off. Experience in client-facing roles and agile teams with specific focus on component-based user interface systems.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## Web Developer Pear Design

Feb. 2017 - Present

Designed web and mobile applications focusing on component systems using tools for prototyping, client feedback, and developer hand-off.

Developed websites and web applications independently and within agile teams with a front-end focus in Javascript ES6, React, and Django.

Oversaw agency contracts, working with clients and developer teams to manage Scope of Work, Specifications and subcontractor agreements.

#### **RECENT PROJECTS**

Impakt Aug. 2018 - Present

Designed browser extension to display ethics data on companies and products through inline alerts on Amazon product and search pages.

Worked with product owners, research partners, and developer teams to update designs to meet evolving product requirements and capabilities.

Designed and assisted in developing product marketing and community blog website with Django REST, Wagtail CMS and BEM SASS.

## **Happy Active Family**

Nov. 2018 - Feb. 2019

Designed mobile application for active-lifestyle parents to plan and share family-friendly activities, integrated with content and product marketing.

Worked with client and developers to wireframe and prototype features to meet brand strategy, business goals, and address core user needs.

## Assemblyman Robert Karabinchak

Oct. 2018 - Jan. 2019

Designed and developed NJ State Assemblyman's constituent services website in React using GatsbyJS, CSS Modules, and GraphQL.

Integrated GraphQL APIs with content management webhooks enabling continuous deployment linked to existing communications platforms.

## Mari for Michigan

Aug. 2017 - May 2018

Created visual identity for successful first-time political candidate, designing unified brand assets across digital, print and signage.

Designed and developed campaign website with static-content generation, integrated headless CMS, and continuous deployment.

#### **PORTFOLIO**

https://michaeldharrington.com https://github.com/michaeldharrington

This resume is written in HTML5 & BEM CSS3, and is available at: github.com/michaeldharrington.

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

### Design

UI / UX Design Visual Design

Wireframing High-fidelity Mockups

Rapid Prototyping Usability Testing

## Development

Javascript ES6+ Python / Django

React REST API
GraphQL Redux
Node.js npm

GatsbyJS HTML5 / CSS3
CSS Modules SASS/LESS
PostGreSQL WordPress
Webpack Babel

jQuery Unit Testing CI/CD; Travis CI WCAG 2.0

#### **Tools**

Figma Sketch
InVision Framer X
Abstract Adobe CC
Git & GitHub Linux

#### EDUCATION

## Rutgers, The State University of New Jersey

B.A. Geography; 2011 - 2015.

Certificates in Urban Planning & Real Estate